Guide to the Salo W. Baron Papers, 1900-1980
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1: Correspondence, 70 linear ft. (140 boxes)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary (JTS), 19671966-1968 (Box 100, Folder 15)
    Louis Finkelstein, Gladys Rosen, David Kogen, Sylvia Snyder
  - Jewish Theological Seminary (JTS), 1968-1969 (Box 100, Folder 16)
    Menahem Schmelzer, David Kogen, Sylvia Snyder, memoranda
  - The Russian Jew, 1962-651962-1964 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    letters with publishers
  - The Russian Jew, 1962-651964 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    Morris Fine, letters with publishers
  - The Russian Jew, 1962-651964-1965 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    Joseph Shubow, Michael Florinsky
  - Jewish Social Studies (JSS), 19641964 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    Alan Stroock, financial report
  - Jewish Social Studies (JSS), 1965 1965 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    J.M. Kaplan, Bernard Goldstein, minutes, Meir Ben-Horin, Arthur Hertzberg
  - Jewish Social Studies (JSS), 1966 1966 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    Meir Ben-horn, Abraham Duker, Jacob Agus, financial report, minutes, Milton Konvitz, J.M. Kaplan, J.S. hertz, Boris Margohin
  - Jewish Social Studies (JSS), 1967 1967 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    financial report, harry Starr, Samuel Bhumenfehd, Meir Ben-hlorin, Max Rothschild, Arthur hertzberg, Lhoyd Gartner, J.M. Kaplan, Milton Konvitz
  - Jewish Social Studies (JSS), 1968 1968-1969 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    minutes, financial report, J.M. Kaplan, Meir Ben-Horin, S.D. Goitein, Perry Goldman
  - Jewish Social Studies (JSS), 1969 1969 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    minutes, financial report, Benzion Netanyahu, Perry Goldman
  - Brown University, 1966-68 1966-1969 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Ernest Frerichs, Leon Feldman
  - Brown University, 1963-68 1964-1967 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    Ernest Frerichs
  - Rutgers University, 1966-681963-1968 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    Leon Feldman, Samuel Bhumenfeld, Rutgers University Press
  - Rutgers University, 1963-68 1963-1965 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    Leon Feldman, Cecil Roth, Rutgers University Press
  - Letters, 1960's-- A-B. 1958-1969 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    Tobey Baron Gitelle, Eric Warenstam, Shoshana Baron Tancer, Robert Tancer
  - Letters, 1960's-- C 1960- 1965 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    Henry Wiggins, Columbia University Press
  - Letters, 1960's-- D-E 1964-1969 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    Lilli Diesendruk, Cyclopedia Judaica, Frederick Lachman
  - Letters, 1960's-- F 1945-1967 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    Ludwilc Seidenman, Foreign Claims Settlement Commission (Baron's claim on lost Polish property), Leon Feldman
  - Letters, 1960's-- G 1960-1968 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    personal finances, Tobey Baron Gitelle
  - Letters, 1960's-- h-Q 1962-1968 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    Solomon Grayzel, Jewish Publication Society, Russell Knapp, Macmillan Company, Editorial Paidos (Argentina)
  - Letters, 1960's-- R-T 1957-1968 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    Oskar Rabinowicz, Stuart Rosenberg, Leon Feldman
  - Letters, 1960's-- U-Z 1960-1968 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Letters, 1960's-- Miscellaneous 1963-1968 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Letters, 1959-64 - A-D 1959-1964 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    Bernard Bhumenkranz, Szuhim Baron (relation), Nathan Davis
  - Letters, 1959-64 - E-L 1959-1965 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    Joshua Finkel, Aroa Gantelh, Rudolf Glanz, Ben halpern, Ihans Lamm, J.M. Kaplan, Abraham Karp
  - Letters, 1959-64 - M-R 1961-1964 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    Massadah Press Ltd., Toni Oelsner, Moshe Perimann, Herman Pollack, Stuart Rosenberg, Cecil Roth
  - Letters, 1959-64 - S-Z and unknown 1959-1964 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    Uriel Tal, Hany Wohfson
  - Letters, 1959-64 - Miscellaneous 1960-1964 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    Chaim Bloch, Meir Ben-horn, J.M. Kaplan, Abraham Neumann
  - Letters, 1965 - A-B 1964-1965 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    Herbert Bloom, Myron Berman
  - Letters, 1965 - C-M 1965 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    Max Gottschalk, Moths Fine, S. Eisenstaat, Rudolf Glanz, N.M. Gehber, Solomon Grayzel, Seymour Liebman
  - Letters, 1965 - N-V 1964-1965 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    Toni Oehsner, Arieh Tartakower
  - Letters, 1965 - W-Z 1965-1966 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1965 - Part I 1965 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    Zvi Ankori, Arthur Cohen, Benzion Dinur, H.Z. herschberg, J.M. Kaplan, Mordecai Kaplan, Moshe Gotthieb
  - Letters, 1965 - Part II 1965 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    Seymour Liebman, Malkin, Toni Oelsner, James Parkes, Rachel Wischnitzer
  - Letters, 1966 - A-C 1966 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    Hannah Arendt, Jacob Agus, Bernard Bhumenkranz, Ben Zion Bokser, Ethel Cohen
  - Letters, 1966 - D-G 1965-1966 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    Jacob Neusner, Abraham Duker, Ben Zion Dinur, Leo Fuks, Lloyd Gartner
  - Letters, 1966 - h-L 1965-1966 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    H.Z. I-hirschberg, Isaac Levitats, Abraham Karp
  - Letters, 1966 - M-O 1965-1966 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    Samuel Mirsky, harry Orhinsky, B. Netanyahu, Jacob Neusner
  - Letters, 1966 - P-Z 1966 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    Joshua Prawer, Gladys Rosen, A. Scheiber, Bisig Sihberschlag, Leo Strauss, Shalom Spiegel, Arieh Tartakower, Yosef Yerushalmi
  - Letters, 1967-68 - A-C 1965-1968 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    Jacob Agus, Wilson Bishai, Meir Ben-horn, Bernard Blumencranz, Yitzhak Baer, Ethel Cohen
  - Letters, 1967-68 - D-G 1967-1968 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    Abraham Duker, Malcolm Diamond, Israel Bfros, Sydney Fisher, Meir Fraenkeh, Bhi Grad, Lloyd Gartner
  - Letters, 1967-68 - h-L 1967-1968 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    Joseph heckelman, Seymour Lieberman, Russel Knapp, Louis Kaplan, hans Lamm
  - Letters, 1967-68 - M-N 1967-1968 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    hans Mommsen, M. Meyerhof, Alice Marcus, Jacob Neusner, B. Netanyahu, Simon Noveck
  - Letters, 1967-68 - P-R 1967-1968 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    Lynne Pankonin, Cecil Roth, Gladys Rosen
  - Letters, 1967-68 - S. 1967-1968 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    Shalom Spiegel, Eisig Silberschlag
  - Letters, 1967-68 - T-Z 1967-1968 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    Arieh Tartnkower, Mordecai Wilensky, Max Weinreich, Yosef Yerushalmi
  - Letters, 1969 - A-C 1969 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    B. Bbumenkranz
  - Letters, 1969 - D-G 1969 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    S. Ettinger, Israel Efros, hyman Ettlinger, Leo Fuks, Max Gottschalk
  - Letters, 1969 - h-L 1969 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    Joseph heckelman, J.M. Kaplan, Milton Konvitz, Seymour Liebman, Hans Lamm
  - Letters, 1969 - M-R 1969 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    Gerard Nahon, hany Oriinsky
  - Letters, 1969 - S 1969 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    Stuart Rosenberg, E. Rosenthal, A Schieber, Elena Spiner
  - Letters, 1969 - T-Z 1969 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    Uriel Tal, Justin Turner, Arnold Wiznitzer
  - Letters, 1968-70 - A-B 1968-1970 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    Jacob Agus, President's Report 1940-43 (Conference on Jewish Relations)
  - Letters, 1968-70 - C-D 1969-1970 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1968-1970-- B-G1969-1970 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    Encyclopedia Britannica, Cyclopedia Judaica, National Jewish Monthly, Editora Perspectiva (Brazil), Ernest Frerichs, Leon Feldman, Lloyd Gartner
  - Letters, 1968-1970-- h-J 1969-1971 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    Francis haber, Jewish history Publications Ltd., Jewish Publication Society of America, Chaim Potok, Lesser Zussman, Jewish Social Studies, Perry Goldman, Abraham Duker, Louis - Finkehstein, Jewish Theological Seminary, Jewish Agency-American Section
  - Letters, 1968-1970-- K-N 1969-1970 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    Russell Knapp, Michael Kamman, B. Netanyahu, National Foundation for Jewish Culture
  - Letters, 1968-1970-- P-S 1959-1970 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    Leon Feldman, Columbia University Press, heury Wiggins, Allan haths Cutler, Abraham Schwartz, Ludwik Seidenman (Baron's Polish claim)
  - Letters, 1968-1970-- T-V 1968-1970 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    Shoshana Baron Tancer, Robert Tancer, Tel-Aviv University
  - Letters, 1968-1970-- W-Z 1968-1970 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    Eric Warenstam, George Wise, Tel-Aviv University, Joseph Wuif, Perry Goldman, Abraham Duker, Yosef Yernshalmi
  - Letters, 1971-- A-B 1971-1972 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    Zvi Ankori, American Jewish historical Society, Meir Ben-I-horn
  - Letters, 1971-- C-D 1971 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    Henry Wiggins, Columbia University Press, Michael Kammen, Council of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds, Cecil Franklin, Abraham Duker
  - Letters, 1971-- D-G 1970-1971 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    Shoshana Bytan (niece), Encyclopaedia Judaica, Leon Feldman, herman Finkelstein, American Jewish Committee, Simon Greenberg, William Gresser, Nahum Gohdmann, Yeshayahu (Jesaja) Weinberg
  - Letters, 1971-- h-J 1971 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    Arthur hertzberg, Jewish Publication Society of America, Lesser Zussman, Chaim Potok
  - Letters, 1971-- h-J 1971-1973 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    C.D. hoannides, Jewish Information Bureau, Jewish Publication Society, Lesser Zussman, Arthur hertzberg, Institute of Jewish Affairs
  - Letters, 1971-- K-L 1968-1971 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    Editora Perspectiva (Brazil), Milton Konvitz
  - Letters, 1971-- M-R 1971 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    Arthur Mag, Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture, Raphael Mahler, Joseph Nedava, B. Netanyahu, National Foundation for Jewish Culture, herman Pollack, Stuart Rosenberg, Rutgers University Press, American Jewish Committee
  - Letters, 1971-- S-V 1969-1971 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    Saeculum, Bisig Silberschlag, Shlomo. Simonsohn, George Wise, Tel-Aviv University, Ludwik Seidenman (Baron's Polish claim), N.N. Tur-Sinai, Isadore Twersky, Arieh Tartakower
  - Letters, 1971-- W-Z 1940-1972 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    George Wise, World Jewish Congress, Yeshayahu Weinberg
  - Letters, 1971-- Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    N. Eck, National Foundation for Jewish Culture, Solomon Grayzel, Anita Novinsky, Frederick Lachman, Encyclopaedia Judaica, Jewish Publication Society, Lesser Zussman, Columbia University Press, Louis Finkelstein, Jewish Theological Seminary, Benzion Netanyahu, University of Haifa, George Wise, Tel-Aviv University, Cecil Franklin, Nahum Goldmann
  - Letters, 1971-- Miscellaneous 1971 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    Arthur hertzberg, Leon Feldman, Abraham Karp, Lesser Zussman, Nahum Goldmann
  - Letters, 1971-72--A-F 1971-1972 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    insurance and financial matters
  - Letters, 1971-72 -- G-R 1971-1972 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1971-72 -- S-Z 1971-1972 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1972-- Miscellaneous 1972 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    Leon Feldman, Morris Margohies, Lloyd Gartner, B. Netanyahu
  - Letters, 1972-- Miscellaneous 1972 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    Milton Konvitz, Stuart Rosenberg, Alfred Gottschalk, I-herman Pollack, Solomon Grayzel, I-Henry Wiggins, Walter Menaker, Max - Gruenewald, Uriel Tal, herman Pollack
  - Letters, 1970-72 -- A-B 1970-1972 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    American Academy for Jewish Research, Zvi Ankori
  - Letters, 1970-72 -- C-F 1969-1972 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    Columbia University memoranda, Andrew Cordier, Charles Elster, h.J. Ettlinger
  - Letters, 1970-72 -- G-M 1970-1972 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    Lloyd Gartner, Nahum Gohdmann, Harvard College. memoranda, Arthur Hertzberg, Abraham Karp, Russel Knapp, Milton Konvitz, Seymour Liebman, Morris Margohies
  - Letters, 1970-72 -- N-Z 1971-1972 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    J. Nedava, B. Netanyahu, Toni Oelsner, Raphael Patai, Stuart Rosenberg, S.J. Roth (Institute of Jewish Affairs), Arieh Tartakower, Eric Warenstam, George Wise, Nahum Goldmann (World Jewish Congress)
  - Letters, 1973 -- A-B 1973 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    American Jewish Committee, Jacob Agus, American Jewish historical Society (Abraham Karp), Leo Baeck Institute (Fred Grubel), Meir Ben-Horin
  - Letters, 1973 -- C-G 1970-1973 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    Moshe Davis, Abraham Duker, Leon Feldman, Louis Finkelstein, Lloyd Gartner, Nahum Goldmann
  - Letters, 1973 -- H-0 1973 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    University of Haifa, Herzliah hebrew Teachers Institute, Costas hoannides, Maurice Jacobs, Judaic Studies (Abraham Duker), Israel Kalman, Jack Kaplan, Abraham Karp, Israel Katz, Milton Konvitz, Russell Knapp, Seymour Liebman, J. Nedava
  - Letters, 1973 -- P-S 1973 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    Pioneer Foundation (henning Nelms), Raymond Rubinow, Bisik Silberschlag, Gus Saron
  - Letters, 1973 -- T-Z 1973 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    Professor S. Simonsohn, Geoffrey Wigoder, E. B. Urbach, Chaim Ganel
  - Letters, 1973 -- Miscellaneous 1973 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    Columbia University Press, speech delivered to. United Jewish Appeal, Leo Breck Institute, Holocaust Colloquium, Dropsie University, J. C. hurewitz
  - Letters, 1973 -- Miscellaneous 1973 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    George Fraenkel, S. Simonsohn, Shoshana (niece), Henry Wiggins, Nathan Ades, Abraham Duker, B.I.J. Rosenthal, Leon Feldman, Alexander Altman, Allan Bronfman, Abraham Karp, Geoffrey Wigoder
  - Letters, 1973 -- Miscellaneous1973 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    Yitzhnk Baer, Abraham Duker, Seymour Liebman, Henry Wiggins, Abraham Karp, Arieh Tartakower, Moshe Perlman, Marvin Tokayer, Erwin Rosenthal, Bisig Sihberschlag, Arthur hertzberg, Stephen A. Lieber
  - Letters, 1974 -- A-C 1974 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    Alexander Altmann, Rebecca Fischer (secretary), Isaac Barzilay
  - Letters, 1974 -- A-C 1974 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    R. Ainsztein, Henry Wiggins, Alexander Altmann, Zvi Ankori, Bernard Blumenkranz, Andre Chouraqui, Columbia University Press
  - Letters, 1974 -- D-M 1973-1974 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    Abraham Duker, S. Ettinger, Milton Kovitz, Arthur hertzberg, Michelle Kamhi, Solomon Kaplan, Jewish Social Studies
  - Letters, 1974 -- D-M 1974 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    Moshe Davis, hyman Ettlinger, Leon Feldman, Zvi Ankori, Lloyd Gartner, Jacob Kaplan, Guido Kisch, Isaac Levitats, Seymour Liebman
  - Letters, 1974 -- N-Z 1974 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    National Foundation for Jewish Culture, Conference on Jewish Social Studies (Abraham Dnker)
  - Letters, 1974 -- N-Z 1974 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    National Endowment for the humanities, B. Netanyahu, herman Pollack, G. Saron, Bisig Silberschlag, Siegfried Stein
  - Letters, 1974 -- Miscellaneous 1974 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    Conference on Jewish Social Studies
  - Letters, 1975 -- A-C 1975 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    Jacob Agus, American Jewish Committee (Moths Fine), Zvi Ankori, Leo Baeck Institute (Fred Grubel), Malcolm Bean, Meir Ben-Horn, Werner Cahnman
  - Letters, 1975 -- D-J 1975 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    International Research Institute, Abraham Duker, Leon Feldman, Morris Fine, Israel Goldman, University of haifa, Meir Ben-horn, Fred Grubeh (Leo Baeck Institute), Leo Jung
  - Letters, 1975 -- K-Q 1975 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    Jacob Kaplan, Russell Knapp, Isaac Levitats, Saul Lieberman, Seymour Liebman, Morris Margohies, Joseph Nedava, Aubrey Newman, herman Pohlack
  - Letters, 1975 -- R-T 1975 (Box 114, Folder 4)
    Cecil Roth, Bisig Silberschlag, Urieh Tal, Tel Aviv University
  - Letters, 1975 -- U-Z 1975 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    George Wise, Yosef Yerushaimi, Yeshiva University
  - Letters, 1975 -- Miscellaneous 1975 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    Lloyd Gartner, Marsha Rozenblitt
  - Letters, 1976-- A-B 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    Chimen Abramsky, Louis Finkelstein, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Edward Teller, American Academy of Jewish Research, Miriam Ungar, Ruth Link-Salinger hyman, Marc Tanenbaum, American Jewish Committee, Zvi Ankori, Association for Jewish Studies, Meir Ben-horn, Joseph Bhau, B. Blumenkranz, B'nai B'rith
  - Letters, 1976-- C-D 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    City University of New York, Columbia University Press, Moshe Davis, Abraham Duker
  - Letters, 1976-- B-J 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    Encyclopedia Britannica, Mark Epstein, Leon Feldman, Marvin Fox, Lloyd Gartner, Jane Gerber, Jacob Kabnkoff, Yosef Gorni, Max Gruenewald, Jewish Publication Society, Jewish Restitution. Successor Organization, Ruth Hyman, Ernest Weismann
  - Letters, 1976-- K-M 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    J.M. Kaplan, Guido Kisch, Macmilhian Publishing Co., Peter Jovanovich, Joseph Miner
  - Letters, 1976-- N-R 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    National Endowment for the humanities, Simon Noveck, Michele Ohlgiesser (cousin), Stuart Rosenberg, B. Rosenthal
  - Letters, 1976--S1976 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    Kurt Schubert, Univresity of Vienna
  - Letters, 1976-- T 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 7)
    Shoshana Baron Tancer, Tel-Aviv University, Michael Marrus
  - Letters, 1976-- W-Z 1975-1976 (Box 115, Folder 8)
    George Wise, Jewish Publication Society, Yosef Yerushalmi
  - Letters, 1974-76--1974 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    Jacob M. Kaphan, Isaiah Friedman, Raphael Mahler
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1974 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    Peter Jordanovich, Macmillan Publishing Co., Jewish Publication Society, Gustav Saron, South African Jewish Board of Deputies, Uri Tal, Robert Chazan, Andre Chouraqui, Arnold Wiznitzer, University of Texas, KTAV Publishing house, Jacob Neusner
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1975 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    Columbia University Press, Arthur Zuckerman, Peter Jovanovich, Macmillan Publishing Co., Wolfgang haase, Ruth Link-Sahinger hyman, American Academy for Jewish Research, Werner Cahnman, Jewish Restitution Successor Organization
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1975 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    Ernest Weismann, Jewish Restitution Successor Organization, B. Frerichs, Saul Kagan
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1975 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    Zvi Ankori, Jewish Social Studies, Lloyd Gartner,. Bisig Silberschlag
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1976 (Box 116, Folder 6)
    Jewish Publication Society, Zvi Ankori, University of haifa, American Academy for Jewish Research, Louis Finkehstein
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1976 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    Ruth Link-Salinger hyman, Jewish Publication Society
  - Letters, 1974-76-- 1976 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    American Academy for Jewish Research, Saul Lieberman, Jacob Katz, Ruth Hyman, J.M. Kaplan
  - Letters, 1974-76-- undated (Box 116, Folder 9)
    Louis Finkelstein, Ruth hyman, Lucjan .Dobroszycki
  - Letters, 1974-76-- Harvard Judaica Collection 1973-1975 (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - Letters, 1974-76-- Publications 1973-1977 (Box 116, Folder 11)
    Columbia University Press, Seymour Liebman, Meir Ben-horn, Michael Manus
  - Letters, 1977-- A-D 1975-1977 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    Marc Tanenbaum, American Jewish Committee, Zvi Ankori, Columbia University Press, Moshe Davis, National Endowment for the humanities, Abraham Duker
  - Letters, 1977-- B-O 1975- 1977 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    Leon Feldman, Lloyd Gartner, Benjamin Halpern, Ruth Link-Salinger hyman, J.M. Kaplan, Raphael Mahler, Benzion Netanyahu, Jacob Neusner, Michele Ohlgiesser (cousin)
  - Letters, 1977-- P-Z 1975- 1977 (Box 117, Folder 3)
    herman Pollack, University of Haifa, Uri Tal, Y. Gorni, Tel-Aviv University, Jack Schechter, Michael Marrus, Bphraim Urbach, Arthur Zuckerman
  - Letters, 1977-- Miscellaneous 1974-1977 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    Maurice Wohlgelernter, Tel-Aviv University, Jewish Restitution Successor Organization, Jewish Cultural Reconstruction, American Jewish. historical Society, University of haifa
  - Letters, 1977-- Miscellaneous 1968- 1977 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    Kurt Schubert, Columbia University Press, Lloyd Gartner, National Endowment for the humanities
  - Letters, 1977-- Miscellaneous 1976- 1977 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    Abraham Duker, Tobey Baron Gitelle, Moshe Davis, Jewish Publication Society, Ruth hyman, Zvi Ankori
  - Letters, 1978-- A-C 1977- 1978 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    American Academy for Jewish Research, Moths Fine, Zvi Ankori, Jesaya Weinberg, Columbia University Press, Russell Knapp
  - Letters, 1978-- D-M 1977- 1978 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    Lloyd Gartner, Abraham Duker, Lucjan Dobroszycki, Isadore Twersky, Jewish Publication Society, Guido Kisch
  - Letters, 1978-- N-V 1976-1978 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    National Foundation for Jewish Culture
  - Letters, 1978-- W-Z 1977-1978 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1978-- Miscellaneous 1978 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1979-- A-B 1978-1979 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    American Academy for Jewish Research, Bernhard Blumenkranz, Columbia University Press
  - Letters, 1979-- C-F 1978-1979 (Box 118, Folder 7)
    Werner Cahnman, Naomi Cohen, Columbia University Press
  - Letters, 1979-- 0-P 1979 (Box 118, Folder 8)
    Jacob M. Kaplan
  - Letters, 1979-- Q-Z 1978-1980 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Letters, 1979-- Miscellaneous 1979 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Letters, 1980 -- A-B 1979-1980 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    Zvi Ankori, Isaac Barzilay, Bernhard Blumenkranz
  - Letters, 1980 -- C-D 1980 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    Meir Ben-horin
  - Letters, 1980 -- E-J 1980 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    S.D. Goitein, S. Ettinger
  - Letters, 1980 -- K-L 1980 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    Hans Lamm
  - Letters, 1980 -- M-S1980 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    Jacob Marcus, Jacob Neusner, Paul Mosher
  - Letters, 1980 -- T-Z 1980 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    S. Ettinger, Tel-Aviv University, Yosef. Yerushalmi
  - Letters, 1980 -- Miscellaneous 1980 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Letters, 1981 -- A-L 1980-1981 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    Roberto Baehi, Isaac Barzilay, Ruth Link-Salinger Hyman
  - Letters, 1981 -- M-R 1981 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1981 -- S-Z 1981 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    Yocheved Sussman (niece)
  - Letters, 1981 -- Miscellaneous1981 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    Abraham Duker, I. Barzilai
  - Letters, 1981 -- Miscellaneous1981 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    Chimen Abramsky, Abraham Karp, Roberto Baechi, Arthur Hertzberg, Jacob Neusner, Yosef Yerushalmi
  - Letters, 1981-82 -- A- 1981-1982 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    Isaac Bnrzilay, American Academy for Jewish Research (Harry Orlinsky), American Jewish History (Henry Feingold), Bernhard Blumenkranz, Meir Ben-Horin, Conference on Jewish Social Studies, Inc.
  - Letters, 1981-82 -- D-O 1981-1982 (Box 120, Folder 7)
    David Goldberg, Jacob Kaplan, Marshall Meyer, Jacob Neusner, Harry Orlinsky
  - Letters, 1981-82 -- P-Z 1981-1982 (Box 120, Folder 8)
    Flerman Pollaek
  - Letters, 19821982 (Box 120, Folder 9)
    David Patterson
  - Letters, 1983 1983 (Box 120, Folder 10)
    Gerson Cohen, Isaac Barzilay, David Patterson
  - Letters, 1980-83 -- A-C 1980-1983 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    Chimen Abramsky, Gerson Cohen, Columbia University (Norman Mintz)
  - Letters, 1980-83 -- D-J1980-1983 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    Louis Pinkelstein, Blisabeth Freundlieb
  - Letters, 1980-83 -- K-M 1981-1983 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    Jacob Kaplan, Vera Moreen
  - Letters, 1980-83 -- N-Q 1980-1983 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    Gerard Nahon, David Patterson, Jacob Neusne
  - Letters, 1980-83 -- R-Z 1980-1983 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1980-83 -- Miscellaneous 1980-1983 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    Vera Moreen, David Patterson
  - Letters, 1984 -- A-C 1984-1985 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    Isaac Barzilay, Zvi Ankori, Meir Ben-Horin, Columbia University Press
  - Letters, 1984 -- D-L 1984-1985 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    Gilbert Dahan, Moshe Davis, David Goldberg, Lloyd Gartner, Israel Goldstein, Leo Jung, Abraham Karp
  - Letters, 1984 -- M-R 1984 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    Vera Moreen, Harry Orlinsky, David Patterson
  - Letters, 1984 -- S-Z 1984 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    Stanford University, Szurek, Yosef Yerushalmi
  - Letters, 1984 -- Miscellaneous 1984 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    Isaac Barzilay
  - Letters, 1984 -- Miscellaneous 1984 (Box 122, Folder 6)
    Jacob Kaplan, Eisig Silbersehlag, Lloyd Gartner, Gilbert Dahan
  - Letters, 1985 -- A-C 1985 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    Chimen Abramsky, Zvi Ankori, Roberto Beebi, Isaac Barzilay, Meir Ben-Horn, Morton Berman, Bernhard Blumenkranz, Gersoa Cohen
  - Letters, 1985 -- D-G 1985 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    Shmuel Ettinger, Leon Feldman, Louis Finkelstein (Jewish Theological Seminary), David Goldberg, Israel Goldstein, Alfred Gottschalk
  - Letters, 1985 -- H-J 1985 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    Hebrew Union College, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Leo Jung, Abraham Karp, Russel Knapp (re: Stanford University), Isaac Lewin
  - Letters, 1985 -- K-L 1985 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    George Mandel, David Patterson, Abraham Peek, Jacob Marcus, Vera Moreen, Paul Mosher
  - Letters, 1985 -- M-V 1985 (Box 123, Folder 5)